so now let's look at what happens when
we need to dispatch instructions so this
is the situation in a cycle dispatch
basically needs to consider latching
operations results that are produced and
also deciding which instructions are
ready to execute so in the same cycle
usually we will have both of them so we
will consider a situation where we can
actually kind of at the beginning of the
cycle do this and then towards the end
of the cycle actually choose among the
instructions that are ready to go
none of these instructions are ready to
go so if we did it the other way around
in this cycle nothing would really
dispatch so now let's do it what's going
to happen is when we broadcast the
result we say which reservation station
is producing the result and what the
value is and now what happens is this
the reservation station whose result is
being broadcast
note that this reservation station has
already dispatched is it was executed it
was broadcast etc so now it comes back
here we are now gonna free this
reservation station basically it's
finished its job so the first thing
we're gonna do is free this reservation
station now it's empty and is ready to
receive another instruction that issues
the next thing that we're gonna do is
match this tag against each of the two
operands in each of the reservation
stations so what's going to happen is
rs4 doesn't match so we're not gonna do
anything for this RS 1 here does match
so instead of RS 1 here we are going to
use the value of minus 0.29 for this
instruction it already has a value here
so we don't have to match anything but
RS 1 here does match so we're going to
take the value of 0.29
and here we have another match of 0 this
is minus 0 minus zero point 29 and this
value is already here so this completes
basically what happens when a result is
kind of being broadcast as far as
reservation stations are concerned now
we need to consider which reservation
stations have all of the operands ready
to go
this one doesn't this one does and this
one does because these are going to
different execution
units assuming that an each execution
unit can take one operation per cycle
this instruction rs4 is gonna execute in
the multiplier so the multiplier for a
while it will be busy with the you know
RS for this is a divided and it's gonna
be basically doing this over this and
then here this one is not ready to go so
the only one that can really go here is
this one so what we will be doing for a
while is RS three minus zero point
twenty nine plus two point seventy two
once these are done they're gonna
broadcast the results and this cycle
will repeat